Andrei Wong Espejo

E-mail: awonge01@student.bbk.ac.uk

Twitter: @Andrei_WongE

Github: https://github.com/Andrei-WongE

Cellphone: +44 7341 781 977

SUMMARY

Economist, PhD candidate in Geography, Environment and Development at Birkbeck, University of London, with experience as a research assistant in the development sector. Skills to work with interdisciplinary teams in the data cycle. Has specific experience in monitoring and evaluation, research uptake, social data governance, project management and urban interventions and social assessments. Designed methodologies and tools to monitor the progress of project activities and outcomes. Supported the development of tools and best practices for data integrity. Knowledgeable of IEG evaluative products. Worked in politically and culturally sensitive environments. Speaks and writes English, French, Dutch, and Spanish. Proven adaptability to differing cultural and business environments.

Interests: Inequality, Spatial Social Science, Economic Sociology, Development Economics, Economics of Technical Change, Environmental Economics, Visual Anthropology.

RELEVANT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

International Consultant (03/2015 - ...)

World Bank (Peru/USA)

Knowledge and experience in addressing issues covered by the WB Environmental and Social Framework (ESF) and social safeguards policies, particularly involuntary resettlement, Indigenous Peoples, stakeholder engagement and information disclosure in complex and challenging settings, and across sectors. Experience with grievance redress mechanisms.

Conducted a social assessment for the National Urban Cadastre and Municipal Support Project, using mixed methods to identify the possible impacts/benefits of the project. Conducted 60 interviews with municipal staff and community leaders from 6 districts. Worked with government land formalization entity to develop a comprehensive citizen participation strategy, including a grievance and redress mechanism.

Conducted evaluation for **IEG** whether intended outcomes are measured by results framework indicators and whether they are in fact achieved or not of 41 WB Group Urban, Resilience and Land projects. Identified factors affecting projects' implementation and results after the COVID-19 pandemic using Nvivo for coding of extracts according to a taxonomy of 15 challenges related to stakeholders, country, and project context. Contribute to interrogate the contribution of IDA's WBG financing to improving outcomes related to more, better paid and more inclusive jobs for IPF and PforRs operations.

Developed a social evaluation with a gender approach and the stakeholder participation plan for the Central Emergency Project 911 under the new Environmental and Social Framework. Conducted interviews with women's organizations, staff of the Women's Emergency Centres and operators of emergency lines.

Lead as Country Field Research manager for the implementation of an impact evaluation, ensuring the correct design and rigorous implementation of a RCT. I led critical on-ground activities such as sample recruitment, baseline survey implementation and intervention monitoring.

Lead as Database Analyst of the Results and Performance Team, the implementation of the global M&E strategy of the Global Practice for Education. Supported the collection, analysis, dissemination, put into use of data and evidence with partners of 76 countries, and contributed to the structuring of the team's operational data tools in coordination with the IT team (dashboard and website).

Inter-American Development Bank (IADB), Peru

Collaborated with the conceptual redesign and proposal of a job-training service for vulnerable youth as a targeting specialist. I participated in the elaboration of the criteria for targeting and selecting the beneficiaries of a labour ministry program, using a gender perspective.

Developed the pre-field sample framework for the evaluation of two technical assistance program for native Amazonian communities. I made methodological recommendations on the use of data sources and evaluation methodologies to consider.

National Forest Conservation Programme, Peru

Elaborated a Monitoring and Evaluation proposal for the Conditional Cash/Direct Transfer Mechanism for Native communities in the Peruvian Amazon. Used theory of change to express the change dynamics of a given context and elaborated a set of indicators to evaluate the intervention, following explicitly a sustainable livelihoods approach to understanding the causal pathway of the intervention. Proposed the adoption and strengthening of systems and processes that foster learning and knowledge-sharing (feedback loops and typologies of causal connections) key for bridging the gap between conceptual design and practical implementation.

Ministry of Development and Social Inclusion, Peru

Identified opportunities to improve the poverty targeting algorithm of the Peruvian Household Targeting System (knowledge brokering). Introduced Multiple Correspondence Analysis and analysis of categorical variables to staff. Managed case-by-case issues of grievances. Used R to analyse surveys and databases. In charge of leading a multidisciplinary team that elaborated the urban poverty strategy analytic report. Coordinated with lead consultants to produce evidence-based policy applying inter-institutional and inter-agency coordination capacities.

Global Green Growth Institute (GGGI), Peru

Lead the implementation of monitoring, reporting, and learning activities of a consortium of 3 entities of the AgroFor Project (7M USD). Advocated for and supported high quality project data and management in an online system and contributed to logframe development, supported monthly, quarterly and end of year reports, knowledge sharing and learning, and supported organizational and regional strategy development and implementation.

Research Assistant (11/2013 - 01/2015) Institute of Development Studies (UK)

- Assisted in data collection for the update of the Hunger and Nutrition Commitment Index (HANCI), Global Nutrition Report and in the ANOVA analysis of inter-state comparison of questions regarding hunger and nutrition to relevant stakeholders using STATA.
- Assisted in the organization, management and analysis of the household level database collected in Bosnia and conduct statistical analyses and econometric modelling using Stata, prepared tables and graphs to convey those results for the paper on Formality and Informality of Local Governance Institutions in the Western Balkans.
- Assisted in the elaboration of a poverty and inequality analysis for the Swiss Cooperation Office in Mongolia to serve as a basis to assess the relevance of the Swiss program with a poverty/inequality lens.

Social studies and systems coordinator (09/2011 - 07/2013) Rio Tinto La Granja Project

- Supported the design and implementation of M&E system;
- Lead and supported the identification and implementation of databases and software to manage and analyse socio-economic data;
- Lead qualitative research and analysis;
- Coordinated, monitored and followed up commissioned social studies and consultants;

- Identified the socio-economic data and information required by the community programs by undertaking a gap analysis, under an experimental learning framework (collected, applied and shared knowledge).
- Actively lead the coordination of 4 consultant companies for the elaboration of the Environmental Impact Assessment Study of La Granja Project, and
- Worked in a political and culturally sensitive environment.

Socio-economic Consultant (06/2009 - 04/2011) Golder Associates Peru S.A.

- Participated in the elaboration of a dozen Environmental Impact Assessment Studies and Social Baseline Studies of mining projects;
- Conducted statistical and survey analysis using STATA;
- Participated and supervised survey fieldwork;
- Led a team of data entry clerks;
- Conducted cost-benefit analysis of mining projects;
- Responsible for elaborating an economic evaluation of environmental impacts;
- Actively participated in the elaboration of Community Relations and Engagement Plans, proposing potential mitigation measures, including potential resettlement issues, and
- Participated in the preparation and conduct of informative workshops to native communities.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Environmental Economics Course (11/2011 –11/2011) Institute of natural sciences, territory and renewable energy – Pontifical Catholic University of Peru

Facilitated a seminar regarding how to elaborate an economic evaluation in the context of an Environmental Impact Assessment report.

Econometrics Tutor (04/2008 - 06/2008) Pontifical Catholic University of Peru

Helped first-year students form the Master in Economics to develop a better understanding of econometrics principles and concepts, by trying to enhance their abilities to apply econometric analysis to address several economic topics.

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Review and proposal of coding process automation using Large Language Model/AI – World Bank (USA) 2023

Qualitative review and content analysis of Urban, Resilience and Land projects effectiveness – World Bank (USA) 2022

The Displacement, Placemaking and Wellbeing in the City – IDS (UK) 2020 National Urban Cadastre and Municipal Support Project – World Bank (Peru) 2019 National Urban Poverty Strategy – Ministry of Development (Peru) 2017

PUBLICATIONS AND COLLABORATIONS

How do governments measure migrants' well-being? A systematic data availability and datasets review (2023 - Wellbeing, Space and Society)

Author (Under review).

Government Statistics and Measures of Wellbeing (2021 - IDS)

Author, funded by Economic and Social Research Council (https://bit.ly/3shNv4Y).

Economic Impact of COVID-19 in the Global Value Chain of Peru (2020 - World Bank)

Research assistance in data analysis (Under review).

The Multidimensional Impacts of Conditional Cash Transfer Program Juntos In Peru (2019)

Research assistance in data analysis (https://bit.ly/4bb1rEv).

<u>awongespejo@worldbank.org</u>

Urban Poverty Profiles (2017 - Ministry of Social Inclusion and Development)

Led a team of economists and sociologists producing a report necessary for the National Urban Poverty Strategy.

<u>Informality matters: Citizen Participation and Service Delivery in Bosnia and Herzegovina (2015-IDS and SDC)</u>

Data management and econometric analysis (https://cutt.ly/PVeDwWQ).

Mongolia Poverty and Inequalities Analysis (2014- Swiss Agency for Development and Cooperation)

Data management and econometric analysis.

EDUCATION

PhD candidate in Geography, Environment and Development (2023) at Birkbeck, University of London

Causal Analysis Workshop (2022) with Scott Cunningham (Baylor University)

Economic Foundations of Urban Analysis (2020) at Lincoln Institute

Spatial Analysis, Land Use and the Environment Summer School (2020) at Pacific University and NOVA School of Business & Economics (Portugal)

Specialization Course in QGIS (2019) at Social Data Consulting Group

MA in Poverty and Development (Distinction) (2013 – 2014) at Institute of Development Studies, United Kingdom

Implementing Randomized Evaluations (2012) at Abdul Latif Jameel Poverty Action Lab

Advanced STATA for applied research (2011) at the CIDDEA

BSc in Social Sciences with a major in Economics (2007) at the Pontifical Catholic University of Peru

LANGUAGES SKILLS

English: Full professional **French:** Professional working **Dutch:** Professional working

Spanish: Native Portuguese: Intermediate professional working

COMPUTER SKILLS

- Highly computer literate in Windows environment with proficiency in Excel, Project, Word, PowerPoint, and PowerBI.
- Experience with Unix Command Line, Quarto, ArcGIS, Qgis, SQL, NVIVO, Git version-control system and Tableau.
- Highly skilled in statistical software packages and languages such as STATA, CSS, R markdown, Python and R.
- Highly skilled in project management software such as Trello, Slack, Discord, Google Docs/Drive, webinar tools and common internet applications.

ACTIVITIES AND SOCIETIES

- Pluralist Economics at Sussex (PEAS)
- Young Scholar Initiative (YSI)
- Social Protection Ambassador (IPC-UNDP)
- Project Access: Head of Mentor Experience & Service Strategy

awongespejo@worldbank.org